Guide to the Terry Tempest Williams Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Papers prior to 2002, 1872-2002 bulk: 1967-2002; Series I
  - Native Americans, Storytelling, other, 1981-1982
    - Animals of the North, by William O. Pruitt, Jr. - excerpts (Box 80)
    - "Landscape as Story (The Navajo Way)" - notes (Box 80)
    - "Navajo Tapestry" - Florence R. Krall (Box 80)
    - Navajo History notes (Box 80)
    - Native American poetry (Box 80)
    - The American Indian Mind (Box 80)
    - "Earth and Story: A Revival of Relationships as Shown through the Navajo Way", 1981 (Box 80)
    - Native American Articles (Box 80)
    - Four Sacred Mountains (Box 80)
    - Native American Bibliography (Box 80)
    - Beads and Ribbons - "The Storyteller", 1982 (Box 80)
    - Ideas for stories (Box 80)
    - Storytelling, 2 (Box 80)
    - A Naturalist's Notes - for "A Naturalist's Notebook" column in Deseret News, 2 (Box 80)
  - Correspondence, 1994
    - Letters written by TTW (Box 81)
    - Correspondence which mentions attachments that were not attached (Box 81)
    - Correspondence - Requests and Invitations, 4 (Box 81)
    - Brandt and Brandt (Box 81)
    - Publishers (Box 81)
    - Universities and Colleges (Box 81)
    - Friends, 5 (Box 81)
    - T. H. Watkins, The Wilderness Society (Box 81)
    - Correspondence re. Utah Centennial Reader (Box 81)
    - Correspondence re. Speaking Engagements (Box 81)
    - Conservation Organizations (Box 81)
    - National Park Service (Box 81)
    - Correspondence - children (Box 81)
    - Hospice - Michelle Craig (Box 81)
    - Pamela Henstell, Pantheon (Box 81)
    - Natalie Taylor (Box 81)
    - Barbara Earl Thomas (Box 81)
    - Sandy Tilcock, Bookbinder (Box 81)
    - Fan Mail and Thank You Notes, 3 (Box 81)
    - Correspondence - miscellaneous (Box 81)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 81)
  - Coyote's Canyon; Book tours, Manuscripts, 1988-1995
    - Proposal to Gibbs Smith of Anthology of Mormons on Landscape, Community and a Sustainable Life (Box 82)
    - Coffee House Press (Box 82)
    - Book publicity (Box 82)
    - Book tours (Box 82)
    - UTNE Reader Visionfest - TTW a presenter, notes for speech, 1995 (Box 82)
    - Coyote's Canyon - photographs by John Telford, stories by TTW (Box 82)
    - Coyote's Canyon - stories, 2 (Box 82)
    - Coyote's Canyon - final manuscript, 1988 (Box 82)
    - Coyote's Canyon - working pages, 2 (Box 82)
    - "Local Color--The Lives and Lands of Southern Utah" (Box 82)
    - "Easter Sunday-the Nevada Test Site", 1992 (Box 82)
    - Desert Quartet - type proof (Box 82)
    - Desert Quartet - Mary Frank (Box 82)
    - Desert Quartet - reviews (Box 82)
    - Paper on Desert Quartet written by Elissa Gutt (Box 82)
    - "Uncle Alan's Baptism" - TTW (Box 82)
    - "Bravo 20 the Bombing of the American West" and "Woman Who is a Tailor" - TTW (Box 82)
    - Conferences (Box 82)
    - International Skye meeting, TTW speech, notes, 1994 (Box 82)
    - Lannan Foundation, 1994 (Box 82)
    - Paper presented at American Academy of Religion, 1994 (Box 82)
    - Commencement Address given by TTW, College of Natural Resources, University of California at Berkeley, 1995 (Box 82)
    - City Arts and Lectures, Inc., 1995 (Box 82)
    - Wallace Stegner Lecture Series - TTW, Peninsula Open Space Trust, 1995 (Box 82)
    - News Releases, 1995 (Box 82)
    - Lizard Woman (Box 82)
    - A Geography of Hope (Box 82)
    - "September, October, November" - TTW (Box 82)
    - Reviews of Counting Sheep by Gary Paul Nabhan, 1993 (Box 82)
  - Utah Wilderness Bill, Miscellaneous, 1995
    - Land and Watershed (Bear Lake level) (Box 83)
    - News articles on Utah Wilderness, 1995; 3 (Box 83)
    - Copy of Hatch and Bennett Wilderness proposal; TTW letter to Charles Wilkinson (Box 83)
    - "The Utah Wilderness Bill" - Charles Wilkinson, 1995 (Box 83)
    - Utah Wilderness Coalition, Wasatch Front Wilderness Activist Meeting (Box 83)
    - TTW draft of 5.2 million acres for Utah Wilderness (Box 83)
    - Sample letters, speeches-notes for Utah Wilderness (Box 83)
    - Statement of Terry Tempest Williams before Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands, 1995 June 23 (Box 83)
    - TTW - articles in New York Times re. Wilderness Bill, 1995 June (Box 83)
    - President's Council on Sustainable Development, Western Regional Team - draft, notations (Box 83)
    - "A Landscape of the Imagination" - TTW (Box 83)
    - "A Tithe to Creation" - TTW; also under the title, "A Landscape of the Imagination" (Box 83)
    - Testimony - manuscript (Box 83)
    - Press Conference - Testimony, 1995 September (Box 83)
    - TTW Notebook (Box 83)
    - Land and People - Conversation with Terry Tempest Williams (Box 83)
    - Naturalist-in-Residence responsibilities; also Lecture Series, Utah Humanities Council (Box 83)
    - Southern Utah Wilderness Alliance (Box 83)
    - The Utah Wilderness Coalition, 1995 (Box 83)
    - The Boston Phoenix - TTW, p. 17 (Box 83)
    - Orion, Correspondence (Box 83)
    - Conference - Orion Society, Office of Poet Laureate, Washington, D.C., 1995 (Box 83)
    - Wild Earth (Box 83)
    - Jodi F. Solomon Speakers Bureau - Common Boundary Conference (Box 83)
  - Personal Japan trip, Reviews, Manuscripts
    - Brooke Williams (Box 84)
    - Personal - pages from datebook, 1992 (Box 84)
    - Personal - pages from datebook, 1994 (Box 84)
    - Personal - Katherine Tempest astrological reading (Box 84)
    - Birthday mementos (Box 84)
    - Papers written for Philosophy of Education, 1994 (Box 84)
    - "Healing the Inner Vermin" - Leslie Ryan (Box 84)
    - Reviews, Interview (Box 84)
    - Essay on TTW Refuge for Western Literature Conference - by Michele Potter (Box 84)
    - Reviews/correspondence re. Refuge; An Unspoken Hunger (Box 84)
    - Correspondence re. Refuge (Box 84)
    - Correspondence re. An Unspoken Hunger (Box 84)
    - Reviews- An Unspoken Hunger (Box 84)
    - Clinton Green Summit - Jackson Hole News, 1995 August 30 (Box 84)
    - Note and manuscript from Susan Turgale (Box 84)
    - "Communion" - TTW, first draft (Box 84)
    - The Nation - "A 'Downwinder' in Hiroshima" - TTW, correspondence, notes, 1995 (Box 84)
    - Japan Trip, 1995 (Box 84)
    - Notes on storytellers (Box 84)
    - Broadcasts (Box 84)
    - Conferences (Box 84)
    - Deerfield, Massachusetts - responses to TTW presentation (Box 84)
    - University of Portland (Oregon) Schoenfeldt Distinguished Writers, 1995 (Box 84)
    - The Erotica Museum in Copenhagen, Denmark, 1993 (Box 84)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 84)
    - News Clippings (Box 84)
    - National Geographic, magazine, 1995 November (Box 84)
    - New Yorker, magazine, 1995 December - 1996 January (Box 84)
    - Outside, magazine, 1995 December (Box 84)
    - Northern Lights, publication, 1992 (Box 84)
  - Day Planners, 1988-1989; 1992; 2 (Box 85)
  - Personal, Correspondence, Desert Quartet, 1989-1994
    - Personal (Box 86)
    - Callie Tempest, "Terry Tempest Williams" (Box 86)
    - Derrick Jensen interview with TTW, draft with TTW notations (Box 86)
    - TTW Notebook, Day Planner pages (Box 86)
    - TTW Daybook, 1989 (Box 86)
    - Spain (Box 86)
    - Correspondence - Requests and Invitations (Box 86)
    - Friends, 2 (Box 86)
    - Fan mail and thank yous (Box 86)
    - Brandt and Brandt (Box 86)
    - Publishers (Box 86)
    - Ellen W. Chu re. Robert D. Anderson book (Box 86)
    - Natalie Goldberg, Ghost Ranch (Box 86)
    - Rita Townsend, poems (Box 86)
    - Tom Wolf (Box 86)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 86)
    - Desert Quartet, drafts, 3 (Box 86)
    - TTW, "Brush Strokes" (Box 86)
    - Notes, TTW, 1994 June 2 (Box 86)
    - TTW Notes (Box 86)
  - Articles, Conferences, Reviews, 1989-1995
    - News clipping: Wallace Stegner, 84, not adequately acknowledged by eastern press (Box 87)
    - Edward Abbey, Memorial Service, 1989 May; 2 (Box 87)
    - Random pages - letters, journal around death of Ed Abbey (Box 87)
    - Tribute to Karen Shepherd p. 14 of 59 (Box 87)
    - Review by TTW of The Moon by Whale Light by Diane Ackerman (Box 87)
    - Essay by TTW, Orion, p. 36-37; Wilderness, TTW on Board (Box 87)
    - Round River Conservation Studies, 1995 (Box 87)
    - Conferences and Workshops (Box 87)
    - Western Literature Conference, volume 1: Wilderness, The Spirit Lives, 1994 (Box 87)
    - 6th National Wilderness Conference, 1994 (Box 87)
    - 100 Visionaries (Box 87)
    - The Wilderness Society, correspondence (Box 87)
    - The Wildlands Project (Box 87)
    - Northern Lights, board meeting, 1990 (Box 87)
    - Grant application, Abramyam String Quartet with TTW as literary voice (Box 87)
    - Matisse retrospective, notes (Box 87)
    - Notes for essays/talks on women (Box 87)
    - Notes for talks: Kittredge Introduction; Denver Museum of Natural History, 1993-1994 (Box 87)
    - The Stranger, letter from Daniel Oko, 1994 (Box 87)
    - Reviews of An Unspoken Hunger, 1994 (Box 87)
    - Reviews, 2 (Box 87)
    - New England Review, articles (Box 87)
    - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 87)
  - Correspondence, News articles
    - Letters written by TTW (Box 88)
    - Correspondence from friends (Box 88)
    - Sandra Lopez (Box 88)
    - Jacqueline M. Ehlis (includes photocopy of photo) (Box 88)
    - Paul Shepherd, Florence Krall (Box 88)
    - Glen Lathrop (Box 88)
    - Brandt and Brandt (Box 88)
    - Requests and Invitations (Box 88)
    - Universities and Colleges (Box 88)
    - Utah Museum of Natural history (Box 88)
    - Publishers (Box 88)
    - Vintage Books (Box 88)
    - Fan Mail and Thank Yous (Box 88)
    - News Articles; copies of four publications (Box 88)
    - Northern Lights, publication, 1993-1995 (Box 88)
    - Various catalogs and Catalyst, publication, 1990s (Box 88)
  - TTW Manuscript notes; Environmental Organizations; Conferences and Symposiums; Miscellaneous, 1994-1996
    - The Atomic Ghost; TTW speech notes, article in Network p. 10-13, 1995 (Box 89)
    - TTW, "Seafloor to Sagebrush--Prologue: The Orange Circle" (Box 89)
    - Breast Cancer, research (Box 89)
    - Grants, Fellowship (Box 89)
    - Environmental Organizations (Box 89)
    - Columbia River Inter-Tribal Fish Commission p. 15 of 59 (Box 89)
    - Cascade Times, Warren Nistad, 1995-1996 (Box 89)
    - Environmental Studies, Dartmouth College, 1996 (Box 89)
    - Great Basin News (Box 89)
    - The Nature Conservancy (Box 89)
    - Snake River Institute (Box 89)
    - Southern Utah Wilderness Alliance (SUWA) (Box 89)
    - Wild Duck Review, Casey Walker, 1996 (Box 89)
    - Wildlife Damage Review, 1996 (Box 89)
    - Conferences and Symposiums (Box 89)
    - Wallace Stegner and the Continental Vision Symposium, Madison, Wisconsin, 1996 (Box 89)
    - The Writer's Voice (Box 89)
    - National Writer's Voice Project (Box 89)
    - Writer's at Work (Box 89)
    - Literary Sojourn, Steamboat Springs, Colorado, 1995 (Box 89)
    - Film Productions (Box 89)
    - Poetry in Commotion, taped show TTW, 1994 (Box 89)
    - Joan R. Bird, "How Tepees Returned to Pine Butte (Box 89)
    - Review of Refuge in Dialogue (copy) (Box 89)
    - Miscellaneous notes and messages (Box 89)
    - Joel Harding manuscripts (Box 89)
    - Miscellaneous manuscript materials from others (Box 89)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 89)
  - Personal, Family Correspondence, TTW writings, 1970-1980
    - Personal (Box 90)
    - Family (Box 90)
    - Day Planner, 1995 (Box 90)
    - Awards (Box 90)
    - Lannan Literary Fellowship, 1993 (Box 90)
    - Phone messages, notes, Natalie (Box 90)
    - Miscellaneous, schedules, lists (Box 90)
    - Book tours (Box 90)
    - TTW miscellany (Box 90)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts - TTW notes (Box 90)
    - Photos (Box 90)
    - Film (Box 90)
    - "My Philosophy of Teaching" - TTW (Box 90)
    - Notebook, 1974 (Box 90)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, TTW, 1970s-1980s (Box 90)
    - Chapter Summaries for "The Urban Naturalist", 1980 (Box 90)
    - Viking Penguin, Inc. agreement for Refuge, 1987 (Box 90)
    - Calendar quotes - TTW (Box 90)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 90)
    - News clippings (Box 90)
    - Magazines and newspapers, circa 1987 (Box 90)
  - Brooke Williams manuscripts, some publications, and correspondence
    - Newspaper clippings and magazines (Box 91)
    - Utah Ski Country - Brooke Williams (Box 91)
    - TTW and BW personal (Box 91)
    - "Bones" by Brooke Williams, Utah State University Magazine, 1995 (Box 91)
    - Magazines (Box 91)
    - Brooke correspondence (Box 91)
    - Magazines and clippings, 1994-1995 (Box 91)
    - "A Great Bear Awakening" by Carl D. Esbjornson (Box 91)
    - "The Dance of a Dissident Daughter" by Sue Monk Kidd (Box 91)
    - "Walking it Off" by Doug Peacock (Box 91)
  - Manuscripts: TTW and others, 1987-1995
    - "Walking it Off" by Doug Peacock (Box 92)
    - Rick Paul Springer, Excuse Me, Mr. President, 1995 (Box 92)
    - A Remembered Landscape, Jackson Hole, TTW draft, 1988 (Box 92)
    - "Unknown Utah," Utah Holiday, 1988 (Box 92)
    - Coyote's Canyon, draft with comments from Carl Brandt (Box 92)
    - Coyote's Canyon, manuscript (Box 92)
    - Refuge, proposal/outline (Box 92)
    - Refuge, proposal, 1987 (Box 92)
    - Refuge, "In the Company of Birds," "Great Salt Lake" (Box 92)
    - TTW, "Earthly Messengers" (Box 92)
  - Manuscripts: TTW and others
    - TTW, Book Jackets (Box 93)
    - TTW in Pequod, "Winter Solstice at the Moab Slough: (Box 93)
    - TTW, "A Landscape of the Imagination: (Box 93)
    - TTW, "The Necklace" and "How Nature Informs Our Lives" (Box 93)
    - TTW notes on article by Deena Metzger (Box 93)
    - TTW, "A Dance with Longing" (Box 93)
    - TTW, "There Are Two Words You Must Learn" (Box 93)
    - "Oh Beautiful Girl! Shining Girl" (Box 93)
    - Sandra Alderman, "Weaving Memories,A" TTW, "Sources of Inspiration..." (Box 93)
    - Writings by Kate Fuller (Box 93)
    - Sandra Lopez and Owl Feather (Box 93)
    - Dorothy Soloman, "From the Aerie" (Box 93)
    - Jack Turner, "The Maze and Aura" (Box 93)
    - Al Warneke correspondence, stories (Box 93)
    - Charles Wilkinson, "Arnie Bollo: Dean of the Western Forests" (Box 93)
    - "Land of Promise Kingdom of Stone" (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous publications and articles (Box 93)
  - Desert Quartet drafts; M. Frank artwork
    - Desert Quartet, correspondence, manuscript materials (Box 94)
    - Desert Quartet, drafts, 6 (Box 94)
    - Mary Frank drawings, copies of drawings considered for Desert Quartet, 5 (Box 94)
  - Refuge: manuscript, reviews, 1993-1996
    - Proposal, sample chapters (Box 95)
    - Refuge - research (Box 95)
    - Draft (Box 95)
    - Oregon Natural Resources, yew tree (Box 95)
    - Suzanne Ross, review; Grant T. Smith, paper, 1993 (Box 95)
    - Patricia Miller, review and letter, 1994 (Box 95)
    - Lois Ipson Green, review; Michele Potter, paper, 1995 (Box 95)
    - Writings about Refuge (Box 95)
    - Reviews, 2 (Box 95)
    - News clippings, publications, 2 (Box 95)
    - Journal and magazine, 1995-1996 (Box 95)
  - Manuscripts
    - Where Canyon Walls Rise Upward Like Praying Hands" - TTW (Box 96)
    - "Clearcut" - TTW - first draft, second draft, 1996 (Box 96)
    - "The Dream of Cranes" - TTW (Box 96)
    - "Bedrock Democracy" - TTW (Box 96)
    - "The Land of Little Rain" - TTW (Box 96)
    - First Draft, "Desert Tortoise" (Family Construction) (Box 96)
    - "Richard Misrach's Bravo 20: The Bombing of the American West" - TTW (Box 96)
    - Sandra Lopez, "Art of the Woods" - by TTW (Box 96)
    - "The Evolving State" - TTW (Box 96)
    - "Homecoming"; "Patterns..." - TTW (Box 96)
    - Miscellaneous notes - TTW (Box 96)
    - Timpanogos Concert, 1996 (Box 96)
    - John Berger manuscript (Box 96)
    - "On Women and the Masculine Heritage of Nature Writing" by Carl H. Klaus, 1993 (Box 96)
    - "Meditation on the Unabomber..." by Ann Kreilkamp (Box 96)
    - "Luck" by Christopher Merrill (Box 96)
    - "Feeding Time at Tango Hotel" - Bob Reiss (Box 96)
    - "The Wingate and Time" - Charles Wilkinson, 1995 (Box 96)
    - Miscellaneous writings (Box 96)
    - The Schoenfeldt Distinguished Writers, 1995 (Box 96)
  - Correspondence, alphabetical subject
    - Lyn Dalebout (Box 97)
    - Brian Doyle (Box 97)
    - Jesse Wolf Hardin (Box 97)
    - Florence Krall (Box 97)
    - Sandra Lopez (Box 97)
    - Edward Lueders (photos) (Box 97)
    - Tom Lyon (Box 97)
    - Olivette Orme (Box 97)
    - Dan Petersen (Box 97)
    - Dave Petersen (Box 97)
    - Edwin P. (Phil) Pister (Box 97)
    - Linda Harris Pritchhard (Box 97)
    - David Rosenberg (Box 97)
    - Karen Shepherd (Box 97)
    - Page Stegner (Box 97)
    - Jean Walkinshaw, KCTS 9 (Box 97)
    - Kathryn Wilder (Box 97)
    - Alec Wilkinson (Box 97)
    - Brandt and Brandt (Box 97)
    - Publishers, 2 (Box 97)
    - Coffee House Press (Box 97)
    - High Country News, Ed Marston TTW on Stegner talk/essay (Box 97)
    - Gibbs Smith Publisher (Box 97)
    - Loose Goose press (Box 97)
    - Milkweed Editions (Box 97)
    - University of Utah (Box 97)
    - Utah Natural History Museum (Box 97)
    - Naturalist-in-Residence, job description notes (Box 97)
  - Correspondence, Friends, 9 (Box 98)
  - Correspondence, Friends, 3 (Box 99)
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous Business (Box 99)
    - Letters written by TTW, 2 (Box 99)
    - Colleges and Universities, 2 (Box 99)
    - Requests and Invitations, 4 (Box 99)
    - Requests (Box 99)
    - Request for permission to quote TTW, Karen Kaufman (Box 99)
  - Correspondence; Talks, 1990-1996
    - Fan mail and Thank Yous, 5 (Box 100)
    - Loose pages, unrelated odds and ends (Box 100)
    - Talks (Box 100)
    - Academic talks, miscellaneous (Box 100)
    - Talks and Speeches (Box 100)
    - Scott M. Matheson Wetland Preserve, 1996 (Box 100)
    - The National Writer's Voice Project (Box 100)
    - TTW, Notes for introduction of Paul Shepherd (Box 100)
    - "A Service of Thanksgiving for the life of Wallace Stegner," program, "The Geography of Hope-A Tribute to Wallace Stegner," program (Box 100)
    - "Burning Sage at the Department of Interior," TTW remarks in remembrance of Wallace Stegner, 1993 (Box 100)
    - Tribute to Wallace Stegner by Bretchen Holstein Schoff (Box 100)
    - Deseret News review of Wallace Stegner's Collected Stories, 1990 (Box 100)
  - Environmental Concerns, Organizations, 1989
    - Environmental Concerns, 4 (Box 101)
    - News articles re. environmental concerns (Box 101)
    - Charles Wilkinson, "The Yellowstone Ecosystem...," draft for discussion (Box 101)
    - Audubon (Box 101)
    - The Nature Conservancy (Box 101)
    - Orion Society and Magazine, 2 (Box 101)
    - Southern Utah Wilderness Alliance (SUWA) (Box 101)
    - The Trust for Public Land (Box 101)
    - Women's Voices for the Earth (Box 101)
    - The Wilderness Society (Box 101)
    - TTW notes, panel, Advocacy and Literature (Box 101)
    - Calendar, 1986 (Box 101)
  - Utah Wilderness Bill; Testimony, 1995
    - Utah Wilderness Bill - TTW, 4 (Box 102)
    - "Why?" from Wallace Stegner Journal (Box 102)
    - Tentative mailing list for Testimony p.19 of 59 (Box 102)
    - Utah Wilderness - Testimony, 3 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence re. Utah Wilderness (Box 102)
    - Drafts - Utah Wilderness (Box 102)
    - First drafts for Testimony (Box 102)
    - Notes for Testimony press conference (Box 102)
    - Testimony, printed copy, 1995 September (Box 102)
    - Testimony, correspondence (Milkweed), Preface, typed copy (Box 102)
    - Testimony, galleys (Box 102)
    - Correspondence re. Utah Wilderness Bill (Box 102)
  - Interviews; Conferences and Symposiums, 1988-1996
    - Salt Lake Tribune, interview with TTW by Anna Mathews, 1989 (Box 103)
    - "Terry Tempest Williams" (Box 103)
    - Correspondence re. interviews given, scheduled (Box 103)
    - Martin interview with TTW, 1996 January 29 (Box 103)
    - Interview with TTW notes correspondence (Box 103)
    - Interview, Susan Skog correspondence (Box 103)
    - TTW Interview for Land and People, 1995 June (Box 103)
    - Stephen Fisher Productions (Box 103)
    - Conferences and Symposiums, 3 (Box 103)
    - "Women and Nature: An Awakening," by TTW at Brigham Young University (BYU) Women's Conference, 1988 (Box 103)
    - Bread Loaf Writer's Conference, 1995 (Box 103)
    - Chatham College Conference, 1995 (Box 103)
    - Key West Literary Seminar, 1995-1996 (Box 103)
    - Conference of National Park Cooperating Associations, St. George, Utah, 1996 (Box 103)
    - In the Thoreau Tradition III, 1995 (Box 103)
    - Western Rendezvous, 1995 (Box 103)
    - Japanese Symposium, 1995 (Box 103)
    - Teewinot Retreat Center (Box 103)
    - The Utah Centennial Anthology Project (Box 103)
    - Utah's Future Project 2000 (Box 103)
    - Utah: A Centennial Celebration review (Box 103)
    - State of Utah Natural Resources, Utah Open Lands Conservation Association (Box 103)
    - Western Regional Natural Resources Task Force, 1995 (Box 103)
    - E-Town (Box 103)
  - Date books, Coyote Canyon cover art, Publications, 1987-1995
    - Planner, 1987-1988 (Box 104)
    - Notebook and datebook (Box 104)
    - Audio Press; symposium in Colorado; Greater Yellowstone meeting, 1988-1990 (Box 104)
    - Short essay in Nature Conservancy, 1995 (Box 104)
    - Calendar notations, 1986 (Box 104)
    - Cover art sketch for Coyote Canyon; paste-up (Box 104)
    - Photo brochure for Utah 5.7 wilderness proposal (Box 104)
    - Harper's, 1989 (Box 104)
    - Essay in Common Boundary, 1995 (Box 104)
  - Miscellaneous; Manuscripts, Conference, Talks, 1984-1996
    - "A Naturalist's notebook," TTW column and other clippings (Box 105)
    - Miscellany, 1980-1989 (Box 105)
    - Publications, 1984-1987 (Box 105)
    - TTW (Mary Austin), "The Land of Little Rain" (Box 105)
    - TTW, "Deerskin" (Box 105)
    - Workshops and Conferences (Box 105)
    - Writers' Tribute to Wallace Stegner, 1995 (Box 105)
    - Schoenfeldt Lecture, 1995 October 15 (Box 105)
    - Chatham College, University of Colorado Law School, 1995 (Box 105)
    - Talk in Idaho (Box 105)
    - Reading at YMCA in Phoenix, Scotsdale, and Tempe, Arizona, 1996 (Box 105)
    - National Parks Conference, 1996 (Box 105)
    - Wallace Stegner Symposium, Madison, Wisconsin, 1996 (Box 105)
    - E-Town (Box 105)
    - "Notes from an Oregon Cattle Ranch," manuscript by Sean Gillhan (Box 105)
    - Clippings (Box 105)
    - Distinguished Utahns (TTW listed), 1996 (Box 105)
    - Miscellaneous notes, letters, clippings (Box 105)
    - The Pacific Yew Act of 1991 (Box 105)
    - Day Planner, 1991-1992 (Box 105)
  - Correspondence; Environment; Utah Wilderness Bill; Reviews, 1995
    - Financial/Business (Box 106)
    - Correspondence--miscellaneous notes (Box 106)
    - Brandt and Brandt (Box 106)
    - Correspondence--Publishers (Box 106)
    - Pantheon Books (Box 106)
    - Portland Magazine, Brian Doyle, correspondence (Box 106)
    - Scholastic Network (Box 106)
    - Correspondence--Universities and Colleges (Box 106)
    - Correspondence--Friends (Box 106)
    - Correspondence--Sandra Lopez (Box 106)
    - Correspondence--Bill Murray (Box 106)
    - Correspondence--William Mulder (Box 106)
    - Susan J. Tweit, "Nature Writing" (Box 106)
    - Requests and Invitations (Box 106)
    - Fan Mail and Thank You's (Box 106)
    - Letters written by TTW (Box 106)
    - Environmental Organizations (Box 106)
    - To. Mennen Environmental Foundation (Box 106)
    - Southern Utah Wilderness Alliance (SUWA) (Box 106)
    - Utah Wilderness Bill, 1995; 2 (Box 106)
    - Utah Wilderness, SUWA Bill (Box 106)
    - Testimony (Box 106)
    - Milkweed Editions (Box 106)
    - Interviews with TTW; related correspondence (Box 106)
    - Papers written about TTW books (Box 106)
    - Reviews: Desert Quartet; An Unspoken Hunger; Refuge, other (Box 106)